Guide to the Hanover Royal Music Archive
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- General Music and Books About Music, 1714-1951; Series I; 13.33; (615 boxes)
  - Ulybyshev, Aleksandr Dmitrievich, 1794-1858
    - Nouvelle biographie de Mozart.... 3 volumes. Print (Moscow: Auguste Semen), 1842-1843 (Box 743-745)
    - [Nouvelle biographie de Mozart]. Mozart's Leben.... 3 volumes. Print (Stuttgart: A Becher), 1847 (Box 746-748)
  - Vanhal, Johann Baptist, 1739-1813
    - [Keyboard music]. Not a Spurious Work! Three Solos for the Piano Forte and Three Sonatas for the Harpsichord With an Obligato Accompanyment for a Violin.... Part (kbd). Print (London: J. Bland), undated (Box 141, Folder 744)
    - [Minuet]. Vanhall's Favorite Minuet. For two horns, two violins, and bass. Score. Print (London: Thompson), 1778? (Box 141, Folder 745)
    - [Piano music]. Twenty-four Duettini for the Piano-Forte for Two Performers or One; for the Amateurs.... Print (London: Hindmarsh), 1809 April 20 (Box 749)
      Dedication to Princess Charlotte of Wales
    - [Quintets, violin, viola, bass, horns]. Trois Quintettos Violino, Viola, Basso a Deux Cors de Chase, ad Libitum.... Parts (va, b). Print (London: Bland), 1782 (Box 141, Folder 746)
    - [Sonatas, violin, violoncello, keyboard]. A First Set of Six Sonatas for the Harpsichord or Piano Forte with an Accompaniment for a Violin Obligato and a Violoncello ad libitum.... Parts (kbd, vn). Print (London: J. Bland), undated (Box 141, Folder 747)
  - Vento, Mattia, 1735-1776
    - [Sonatas, keyboard]. A Ninth Book of Six Sonatas for the Harpsichord or Piano Forte.... Print (London: Welcker), 1775 (Box 141, Folder 748)
  - Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 142, Folder 749)
  - Vetterling, G. C.
    - Music. Print, lithograph, undated (Box 142, Folder 750)
  - Victoria Mary Louisa, Duchess of Kent, 1786-1861
    - Grand Miliary March.... For piano. Print (London: Cocks), undated (Box 142, Folder 751)
    - Second Grand Military March.... For piano. Print (London: Cocks), circa 1823-1844 (Box 142, Folder 752)
      Inscribed by the composer
  - Vierling, Georg, 1820-1901
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 142, Folder 753)
  - Vieth, C. L.
    - Gesangschule.... Print, typeset (Arnsberg: Grote), 1854 (Box 750)
  - Vieuxtemps, Henri, 1820-1881
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 751)
  - Vischer, Friedrich Theodor, 1807-1887
    - Aesthetik, oder Wissenschaft des schönen.... Print (Stuttgart: C. Mäcken), 1857 (Box 752)
  - Vivier, Eugène, 1817-1900
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 142, Folder 754)
  - Volckmar, W. (Wilhelm), 1812-1887
    - Music. Print, 1854? (Box 753)
  - Voss, Charles, 1815-1882
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 142, Folder 755-756)
  - Wächter, Heinrich
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 142, Folder 757)
  - Wackernagel, Philipp, 1800-1877
    - Bibliographie zur Geschichte des deutschen Kirchenliedes im XVI. Jahrhundert.... Print (Frankfurt a. M.: Heyder & Zimmer), 1855 (Box 754)
    - Das deutsche kirchenlied von der ältesten zeit bis zu anfang des XVII. jahrhunderts.... 5 volumes. Print (Leipzig, B. G. Teubner), 1864-1877 (Box 755-759)
  - Wade, J. Augustine (Joseph Augustine), 1796-1845
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 142, Folder 758)
  - Wagner, [J.?]
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 143, Folder 759)
  - Wagner, J. H.
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 760)
      Laid in: photograph of an unidentified ship; and notes
  - Wallerstein, A. (Anton), 1813-1892
    - 6 Deutsche Lieder...8tes. Werk.... Score. Print (Hanover: Nagel), undated (Box 143, Folder 760)
    - Kronprinzen-Marsch.... For piano. Print (Hanover: Nagel), undated (Box 143, Folder 761)
      Dedication to the Crown Prince of Hanover
  - Walmisley, Thomas Attwood, 1814-1856
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 761)
  - Webbe, Samuel, 1740-1816
    - Eight Anthems.... Score. Print (London: for the author), undated (Box 143, Folder 762)
    - A Collection of Masses.... Print (London: for the proprietors), 1792 (Box 762)
    - A Collection of Motetts or Antiphons.... Print (London: for the proprietors), undated; (2 copies) (Box 763)
      One copy inscribed: Augusta
  - Weber, Carl Maria von, 1786-1826
    - Aufforderung zum Tanze, Rondo Brillant für das Piano-Forte.... Print (Berlin: Schlesinger), 1821 (Box 143, Folder 763)
    - [Euryanthe. Overture]. Ouverture zur grossen romantischen Oper: Euryanthe, für das Pianoforte eingerichtet.... Print (Vienna: Steiner), 1824? (Box 143, Folder 764)
    - Der Freischütz.... Arranged Carl Zulehner. Vocal score. Print (Mainz: B. Schott Söhne), 1820s? (Box 144, Folder 765)
      Inscribed: H.R.H. Pss. Augusta
    - [Der Freischütz. Overture]. Ouverture aus der Oper: Der Freyschütz.... Arranged for piano. Print (Berlin: Schlesinger), 1821 (Box 144, Folder 766)
    - Oberon.... Arranged for piano by Wustrow. Print (Berlin: Schlesinger), undated (Box 144, Folder 767)
    - [Oberon. Overture]. Ouverture zu der Oper Oberon.... Arranged for piano. Print (Berlin: Schlesinger), 1825 (Box 144, Folder 768)
    - [Preciosa. Overture]. Ouverture zu dem Schauspiel Preciosa.... Arranged for piano. Print (Berlin: Schlesinger), 1821 (Box 144, Folder 769)
    - [Sonata, piano, no. 1, op. 24, C major]. Grande Sonate pour le Pianoforte.... Print (Berlin: A. M. Schlesinger), 1812 (Box 145, Folder 770)
    - Vien qua Dorina Bella...Op. 7. Song with variations for piano. Score. Print (Leipzig: H. A. Probst), 1826 or 1827? (Box 145, Folder 771)
  - Wedgwood, James Ingall
    - Some Continental Organs (Ancient and Modern) and their Makers.... Print (London: Reeves), 1910 (Box 764)
  - Wehner, Arnold
    - Music. Manuscript, 1856, 1866 (Box 145, Folder 772)
  - Weidemann, Ernst
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 765)
  - Weippert, E.
    - [Marches]. For keyboard. Manuscript, undated (Box 145, Folder 773)
      Contents: Trumpet March; Quick March
  - Wellhausen, A.
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 766)
  - Wensley, Frances Foster
    - God save the King, Arranged for the Piano Forte.... Print (London: author), undated; (2 copies) (Box 888)
  - Wenzl, Wilhelm
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 145, Folder 774)
  - Wenzel, Eduard
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 145, Folder 775)
    - Correspondence and notes, 1830s-1840s, undated (Box 145, Folder 776-777)
    - Copies of poems, undated (Box 146, Folder 778-780)
  - Werner, Gregor Joseph, 1695-1766
    - [Neuer und sehr curios-musikalischer Instrumental-Calendar]. Parts (2 vn, b). Manuscript, undated (Box 147, Folder 781-783)
  - Wesley, Charles, 1757-1834
    - The Twelfth of August.... For voices and accompaniment. Manuscript, 1827 July 3 (Box 767)
    - Air with Variation for a Piano Forte or Harpsichord.... Print (London: Birchall), undated (Box 147, Folder 784)
  - Westmeyer, Wilhelm, 1829-1880
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 147, Folder 785)
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 768-769)
      With: note signed by the composer
  - Westmorland, John Fane, Earl of, 1784-1859
    - Music. Print, 1846, undated (Box 147, Folder 786-787)
      With: concert program, print, 1843 March 17
  - Whistling, August
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 148, Folder 788)
  - Widder
    - Cavatine aus der Oper Katharina Cornaro, von F. Lachner, arrangirt...von Widder. Parts (fl, 7 cl, 2 ob, 2 bn, 4 hn, 3 tpt, 3 trbn, bombartini). Manuscript, undated (Box 148, Folder 789)
      Arrangement by "Widder" of music from the opera Catarina Cornaro by Franz Paul Lachner (1803-1890)
  - Wieck, Georg
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 148, Folder 790)
  - Wieprecht, W. (Wilhelm), 1802-1872
    - Music. Manuscript and print, undated (Box 148-149, Folder 791-793)
  - Wilfling, Stefan
    - Music. Manuscript, 1909 (Box 149, Folder 794)
  - Willing, Johann Ludwig
    - [Sonatas, violin, keyboard]. Drey Sonaten fürs Clavier oder Piano-Forte mit Begleitung einer Violine.... Parts (kbd, vn). Print, typeset (Leipzig: J. G. I. Breitkopf), 1787 (Box 149, Folder 795)
    - [Sonatas, violin, keyboard]. Drey Sonaten fürs Clavier oder Piano-Forte mit Begleitung einer Violine...Zweyter Theil. Parts (kbd, vn). Print, typeset (Leipzig: [J. G. I. Breitkopf]), 1788 (Box 149, Folder 796)
  - Winderstein, Hans
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 770)
  - Winkler, Louis
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 149, Folder 797)
  - Winter, Peter von, 1754-1825
    - Timoteo o Gli effetti della Musica...Die Macht der Töne.... Score. Print (Leipzig: Breitkopf & Härtel), 1810? (Box 771)
      Laid in: manuscript alto part for Coro no. 4
  - Winterfeldt, D. v.
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 772)
  - Wittek, Peter
    - Music. Manuscript, 1855 (Box 149, Folder 798)
  - Wittmann, Carl
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 773)
  - Witzleben, Job von
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 774)
  - Wohlfahrt, Heinrich, 1797-1883
    - Music. Print, typeset, undated (Box 149, Folder 799)
  - Wölfl, Joseph, 1773-1812
    - Schirmers Choice Manuscript Collection of Music. First Number. For keyboard and voices and keyboard. Manuscript, 1806? (Box 150, Folder 800)
      With "Plan for a Subscription," print (London), 1806 September 30
    - Schirmers Choice Manuscript Collection of Music. Second Number. For keyboard and voices and keyboard. Manuscript, undated (Box 150, Folder 801)
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 150, Folder 802)
      Titles: The Cabinet, No 2,Consisting of Rondos, Airs, With Variations and Military Pieces, for the Piano Forte (London: Bland & Weller's); Heigho, composed by Mr. Shield & Sung by Mrs Dickons in Two Faces under a Hood (London: Clementi); Castle Goring, A Rondo (London: author); The Much Admired Polacca Composed by Mr Shield and sung by Mrs Dickons, in Two Faces under a Hood (London: Clementi, Banger)
  - Wosahlo, A. C.
    - Music. Manuscript, 1873 (Box 775)
  - Wrede, H. Albert
    - Music. Print, typeset, undated (Box 150, Folder 803)
  - Wüerst, Richard, 1824-1881
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 150, Folder 804)
  - Wulfes, Wilhelm
    - Music. Manuscript, 1868? (Box 150, Folder 805)
  - Zabel, Carl
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 150, Folder 806)
    - Music. Manuscript, 1857 (Box 776)
  - Zambotto, Pietro
    - Marcia per Piano Forte, ed Organo. Keyboard music. Manuscript, undated (Box 151, Folder 807)
  - Zech, J.
    - Music. Manuscript, 1865, undated (Box 151, Folder 808-809)
  - Zelter, Carl Friedrich,1758-1832
    - [Vocal music]. For voice and keyboard. Fragment. Manuscript, undated (Box 151, Folder 810)
      Text by Friedrich Schiller: Was thun, spricht Zeus!
  - Zumsteeg, Emilie, 1796-1857
    - Music. For piano. Print (Bonn: N. Simrock), undated (Box 151, Folder 811)
      Titles: Doppelmarsch; Marche Concertante; Momento Capriccioso (no publisher); Trois Polonoises
  - Zumsteeg, Johann Rudolf, 1760-1802
    - Die Geisterinsel.... Vocal score. Print, typeset (Leipzig: Breitkopf & Härtel), 1799; (3 copies) (Box 777-779)
  - Unidentified
    - Vocal music
      - Affghanistan: Mourn for the Brave...by M. A. M. N..... Song. Print (London: Falkner), undated (Box 151, Folder 812)
      - English and French Songs Composed for the Piano Forte, Harp and Guitar...by a Lady.... Score. Print (London: author), undated (Box 151, Folder 813)
      - [God save the King]. Versions in manuscript and print, 1745-1746?, undated (Box 151, Folder 814)
      - Odes, Songs, and Marches...by an Amateur.... Score. Print (London: author, by Cianchettini & Sperati), 1807 (Box 152, Folder 815)
      - Preussisches Volkslied, Nach dem Englischen Rule Britania.... Score. Print, typeset (Berlin: Amelang), undated (Box 152, Folder 816)
      - Other titles, A-Z. Manuscript and print, undated (Box 152-153, Folder 817-822)
      - Untitled. Manuscript, 1859, undated (Box 780)
      - Untitled and fragments. Manuscript and print, undated (Box 153, Folder 823-825)
    - Keyboard music
      - Ancient Caledonian Melodies...by a Caledonian Lady.... Print (London: compiler), 1827 (Box 154, Folder 826)
        Includes watercolor illustrations
      - [Dance Music]. Waltzes and other dances. Manuscript and print, undated (Box 154, Folder 827-828)
      - [Marches]. Manuscript, undated (Box 154, Folder 829)
        Titles: His Royal Highness The Duke of Gloucesters new Troop; His Royal Highness The Duke of Yorks new Troop; Lord Cornwallis's March; March and Quick Step; The Quick Step of the Royals and The Bath Volunteers March (inscribed: H.R.H. Princess Augusta); Prince of Wales's March; Slow March 3d Guard
      - [Sonatas, keyboard]. Manuscript, with printed covers (Florence: Chiari), undated (Box 154, Folder 830)
      - Other titles, A-Z. Manuscript and print, 1823-1835, undated (Box 155, Folder 831-832)
      - Untitled and fragments, undated (Box 155, Folder 833-834)
        Includes music annotated "Prince George"
    - Instrumental ensemble
      - [Dance music]. Waltzes. Manuscript, undated (Box 155, Folder 835)
      - [Dance music]. Waltzes and other dance music. Manuscript, undated (Box 781)
      - [Marches]. Manuscript and print, 1861, undated (Box 155-156, Folder 836-839)
      - [March]. Manuscript, undated (Box 782)
      - Ouverture Romantique. For orchestra. Score. Manuscript, undated (Box 783)
      - Titles, A-Z. Manuscript and print, undated (Box 156, Folder 840-841)
      - Untitled. Manuscript and print, undated (Box 157, Folder 842-845)
    - Other papers
      - Catalog listing keyboard music, guitar music, songs, and dance music for orchestra. Manuscript, [circa 1837?] (Box 783a)
      - Detached shelfmark labels and other binding fragments, undated (Box 158, Folder 846)
      - Fragments of blank music paper, undated (Box 158, Folder 847)
      - An Heroic Poem to Britannia, in Remembrance of the Jubilee year of George the Third.... Print (London: Allen), 1809 (Box 158, Folder 848)
      - Notes on General History of the Science and Practice of Music, by Sir John Hawkins. Manuscript, undated (Box 158, Folder 849)
      - Photograph of Adelina Patti, undated (Box 158, Folder 850)
      - Printed material relating to the Hof- und Kirchen-Chor, Hannover, 1860-1861 (Box 158, Folder 851)
      - Printed material relating to music vendors, undated (Box 158, Folder 852)
      - Printed material relating to the royal family of Hanover, 1840-1866, undated (Box 158, Folder 853)
- Music Collections, 1651-1868; Series II; 3.25; (132 boxes)
  Series II, Music Collections, is organized in three subseries: Print Music Collections and Series, Manuscript Music Books, and Bound Collections.
  Printed collections consist of series such as publications of the Musical Antiquarian Society and Sammlung von Märschen zum bestimmten Gebrauch der Königlich Preussischen Armée, as well as volumes of music by multiple composers; collections of psalms, chorales and other sacred vocal music; annual keepsakes; and bound journals. Manuscript Music Books are volumes kept by Princess Augusta, Princess Amelia, or other royal family members, containing exercises and copies of vocal and keyboard music. Also present is a volume of music exercises kept by astronomer Caroline Lucretia Herschel. Among the contents of these volumes are a Johann Christian Bach holograph setting of "The Expiring Christian to His Soul," and holograph music of Charles Frederick Horn.
  Bound Collections contain printed vocal and keyboard music. Some volumes also contain manuscript material, including a Johann Christian Bach holograph of "T'adoro te solo eterno mio Dio," a version of the aria from his oratorio Gioas, rè di Giuda. Partial contents for some bound collections are listed in folder notes. Further examination of the contents of music books and bound collections is necessary for complete description of their contents. Volumes in this series contain music by multiple composers; additional bound collections in Series I, General Music and Books About Music, contain music by single composers.
  - Print Music Collections and Series
    - Andächtiger Seelen geistliches Brand- und Gantz-Opfer das ist vollständiges Gesangbuch.... 8 volumes. Print (Leipzig: Zeidler), 1697 (Box 784-791)
    - Apollo's Gift, or, the Musical Souvenir for MDCCCXXXI.... Edited by Muzio Clementi and J. B. (Johann Baptist) Cramer. Print (London: Chappell etc.), 1831 (Box 792)
    - Caecilia, Sammlung von Compositionen alter Ital. Meister.... Edited by Otto Braune. Jahrg. I-II. Scores and parts. Print (Berlin: Verlag des Herausgebers; Bahn), undated; (2 copies) (Box 159-163, Folder 854-873)
    - Choral-Buch für Kirche, Schule und Haus.... Print (Bernburg: Reiter), 1864 (Box 793)
    - Le Delizie dell Opere, Being a Collection of all the Favourite Songs in Score.... Volume VI. Print (London: Walsh), undated (Box 794)
    - Geistliche Betrachtungen.... Print (Königgratz: Tibelli), 1724 (Box 795)
      Bound with additional items
      Manuscript pagination
    - The Harmonist, A select collection of ancient and modern glees, catches, canons, epigrams &c.... Volume I. Print (London: C. Wheatstone), undated (Box 796)
    - The Harmonicon, A Journal of Music.... Volumes I-III. Print (London: Pinnock; Samuel Leigh), 1823-1825 (Box 797-799)
    - Illustrirte Ausgabe erlesener musikalisher Meisterwerke. Erster Band: Klassisches Sopran-Album. Series. Print (Leipzig: Gumprecht), undated (Box 163-164, Folder 874-875)
    - Improved Psalmody.... Volume 1. Collected by William Dechair Tatersall. Score. Print (London: Rivingtons; Leigh; Sotheby), 1794; (3 copies) (Box 800-802)
      Spine title: Tattersall's Improved Psalmody
    - Journal des Dames.... 5 volumes. Print (London: C. Arnoux), 1817-1819 (Box 803-804)
      Contains music, typeset, with dance instructions (1 volume); fashion plates, hand colored (2 volumes); literature (2 volumes)
    - Kirchliche Chorgesänge zum Gegrauch beim evangelishen Gottesdienst... Viertes Heft. Print (Stuttgart: Ebner'schen), 1857; (2 copies) (Box 164, Folder 876)
    - Miniature Lyrics, The Poetry by Thos. Bayly, Esqr., The Airs Composed or Selected by Sir J. Stevenson.... Score. Print (Dublin: Willis), 1823? (Box 164, Folder 877)
    - Musica Sacra. Series. Print, 1850s-1860s (Box 164-166, Folder 878-884)
    - Musica Sacra. Series. Print (Berlin: Schlesinger), 1850s-1860s? (Box 805)
    - Musical Antiquarian Society. Print, 1840s? (Box 167-176, Folder 885-917)
      Music printed for members of the Society (London: Taylor) and (London: Chappell), and similar publications (London: Richards)
    - Musical Antiquarian Society, 1840s (Box 806-807)
      Music printed for members of the Society (London: Chappell)
    - The Musical Bijou, An Album of Music, Poetry, and Prose.... Edited by F. H. Burney. 2 volumes, for 1829-1830. Print (London, Goulding and D'Almaine) (Box 808-809)
    - The Musical Keepsake for the year 1834.... Print (London: for the proprietor) (Box 810)
      Book binder's label: F. Westley…Friar Street
    - Passatempi musicali osia Raccolta di Ariette e Duettini, Romanze Francesi.... Terza Edizione. Parts 1-4. Print (Naples), undated (Box 811)
      Inscribed: Her Royal Highness The Princess Augusta, 1832
      Bound with music for piano, manuscript, in an unidentified hand; and watercolor illustrations
      Part 2 bound out of order
    - Les Pseaumes de David mis en rime françoise, par Clement Marot, & Theodore de Beze.... Print, typeset (Se vendent à Charenton par Antoine Cellier demeurant à Paris), 1651 (Box 812)
    - Sammlung von Märschen zum bestimmten Gebrauch der Königlich Preussischen Armée.... Score. Print (Berlin: Schlesinger)
      - Für Cavallerie-Musik, undated (Box 889)
      - Geschwinden Schrittes. No. 1-49, undated (Box 890)
      - Geschwinden Schrittes. No. 50-89, undated (Box 891)
      - Geschwinden Schrittes. No. 90-118, undated (Box 892)
      - Langsamen Schrittes, No. 1-29, undated (Box 893)
      - Langsamen Schrittes, No. 30-53, undated (Box 894)
      - Original boxes, undated (Box 895-900)
      - Trompeten-Musik, undated (Box 176, Folder 918-919)
      - Tuerkische Musik, undated (Box 176-177, Folder 920-921)
      - [Marches]. No. 52, 102, 106-123, undated; 2 copies of No. 11, 12, and 14 (Box 177-179, Folder 922-930)
      - [March]. No. 156, undated (Box 901)
    - Te Deum Patrem (Grace before Meat).... Vocal music. Print (London: W. Hawes), undated; (2 copies) (Box 179, Folder 931)
    - Trésor Musical. Series. Print (Bruxelles: C. Muquardt), 1865-1868 (Box 179-180, Folder 932-935)
    - Other collections and series. Print, 1846, undated (Box 180-182, Folder 936-943)
    - Other collections and series. Print, undated (Box 813-814)
  - Manuscript Music Books
    - Amelia, Princess, daughter of George III, King of Great Britain, 1783-1810
      - Music book, circa 1798 (Box 815)
        Inscribed: Her Royal Highness Princess Amelia, July 4th, 1798
        Contains songs and dances in various hands
      - Music book, circa 1790s (Box 816)
        Signed by Princess Amelia; initialled by Princess Augusta
        Inscribed by Princess Augusta: Given me by my two Dear Brothers the Prince of Wales and the Duke of Cambridge after my beloved Amelia's death, Nov. 21st, 1810
        Contains music in the hand of Charles Frederick Horn and annotations by Princess Augusta
    - Augusta Sophia, Princess, daughter of George III, King of Great Britain, 1768-1840
      - Music book, circa 1789-1791 (Box 817)
        Inscribed; Augusta Sophia, Queens House, London, 1789
        Contains keyboard music and songs, including in the hands of Charles Frederick Horn (signed, 1790; fingering guide for scales; and an unfinished keyboard draft); Princess Augusta (inscribed The Trip to Weymouth, 1790, AS; and composition drafts); Princess Elizabeth (German Air Ohne Liebe); and Lady Mary Howe (1791)
      - Music book, circa 1790 (Box 818)
        Contains dances, songs, and drafts in several hands, including Charles Frederick Horn; Horn and Princess Augusta (Ye woods and ye Mountains); and other Princesses
      - Music book, circa 1818-1828 (Box 819)
        Inscribed: Augusta...1818
        Contains songs and dances in several hands, including Princess Augusta (Brighton…1828)
      - Music book, circa 1834 (Box 820)
        Inscribed: Her Royal Highness The Princess Augusta May, 1834
        Book binder's label: E. Style, Windsor
        Contains keyboard dances and songs
      - Music book, early 19th century (Box 821)
        Inscribed: Augusta, The Gift of Charlotte...
        Contains waltzes and other dances for keyboard, apparently in two hands
      - Music book, circa 1830 (Box 822)
        Inscribed: Augusta
        Contains vocal and keyboard music, including in the hands of Charles Frederick Horn, (Pleasure submits to pain, with parts assigned to Elizabeth [?], Sophia or Augusta, Mary and Edward); and Princess Augusta (Variations by AS; and sketches and drafts)
    - Friedrike
      - Music book, circa 1829 (Box 823)
        Inscription: Tante Friedrike…1829
        Contains songs and other music
    - Herschel, Caroline Lucretia, 1750-1848
      - Music book, undated (Box 824)
        Inscribed: Carolina Herschel
        Contains exercises and vocal and keyboard music in various hands
    - Unidentified
      - Music book, circa 1787-1789 (Box 183, Folder 944)
        Contains songs, arias, and keyboard and other instrumental music in various hands, including by Princess Augusta (initialled, Windsor December 1st 1787); an early version of Yankee Doodle; by Weidemann and Vinci; two sets of six minuets, possibly in the hand of Frederick Nicolay (For Her Majesty's Birth Day, 1788); and sketch possibly in the hand of Charles Frederick Horn
      - Music book, circa 1780s (Box 825)
        Cover title: Französische Gesänge
        Contains songs in various hands, probably including Princess Augusta; and drafts, probably by one of the Princesses